Visit turkision.com for more!
-What have you done, Osman Bey?
-I did what needed to be done.
Killers.
Not only your sons but also you are killers, Osman!
You are all liars!
You killed the judge to save your killer son!
And you? To get my son killed.
...you killed the real judge
Tell me. Who planned this?
Ibrahim Bey? Yakup Bey?
Why would I kill Rukneddin who...
...I especially demanded to rule the trial?
Was this the easiest way
to kill my son, Ibrahim Bey?
If I had found your son before the trial
...I would have killed him myself! But...
...I didn't want
things to end up here.
I have nothing to do with the judge!
It doesn't matter anymore. The killer has to die.
Nobody can kill my son as long as I breathe.
Attack!
Come on. Come on.
Look at that! Look at that! Look at that!
Alps, stop!
Look at the army of Allah on the ground!
Holy Quran commands...
"Believers fight for the cause of Allah,
...whereas disbelievers
fight for the cause of the Devil.
So fight against Satan's forces.
Indeed, Satan's schemes are ever weak."
Are you faiths...
...weaker than Satan's schemes?
Why are you fighting each other?
A dervish's hat is his shroud.
I put it in front of you. If you are
insistent on shedding brother's blood
..start with us first.
Then you can bury me with my shroud.
And then you'll have all the battlefield to fight.
Neither Germiyans nor Candars...
...would ever swing swords against a dervish.
Put your swords down!
You've come and saved the killers.
Don't you have anything to tell them, Dervish?
They killed my son!
The reason has left. Anger has come instead.
Anger has overwhelmed the mind.
Sultan is the anger now.
It doesn't let you see the world.
I know. Your heart is burning in flames.
But your anger blinds you.
If it's going to help the fire inside you,
...start with me, Melike Hatun.
Today, swords aren't going to be
put back in the sheaths. No peace.
But only war.
There will be a river of blood in the battlefield.
Get ready.
Today is the day to deserve
the bread in your stomachs!
-Attack.
-This jackal intends to restart the fire.
I've already given up on my life, brother.
Even if I'm going to pass away
today, we have to stop them.
Let's go.
Allah is the greatest!
Ulcay!
No jackals will go...
...beyond this place today!
No brother's blood will be shed today!
I am speaking words not to cut off heads...
...but to stop the fight between brothers.
Now the great warriors shall speak.
I have a life to sacrifice
and some words to be heard.
Either you'll hear my words and stop...
.or..
Yunus Emre.
Take this.
Allah is my witness...
...that we didn't draw our
swords to shed brother's blood.
We drew ours swords to wake them
up from the sleep of unawareness.
But if they listen to Sultan of the Words
...then...
...we'll put out swords back in the sheaths.
Yunus Emre is speaking of the truth.
Tugay, go tell Ulcay not to fight anymore.
Finally you've come to reason, Ibrahim Bey.
Osman Bey, we have always been reasonable.
Your recklessness have made us end up here.
For now, there will be no fighting!
Alps, light the arrows.
Neither fire nor swords...
...can stop me today.
-Alps!
-Attack!
Stop!
Ulcay!
A single man, Ibrahim Bey's orders.
Come on!
May the skies be my witness..
..I will strangle you in your sleep.
Everything Yunus Emre says is true.
We were telling you that as well.
That is why we were avoiding conflict.
The reason why we were holding back..
-..is just that.
I do not believe you did these.
Someone is tricking us.
However, we will not fall for
it. We will solve this together.
Will my son come back
after you solve it, Osman Bey?
Your son's vengeance will be
taken when it is solved, Melike Hatun.
You will stop attacking my son.
Hatun!
Enough of this.
This is not the time.
If you want to see the truth..
...the judge's grave is apparent.
Yunus Emre. Since you are
stopping the fight with your word..
..since you put yourself in front
of the sword with your Dervishes..
..then, you are the most qualified person..
..to find my son's killer.
Truth is like sun.
After dark..
..truth always makes itself apparent.
If Beys see it fit..
..I support it.
However, Ulcay will be with you at all times.
Then, there will be one person from each Beylik.
Mehmed Bey..
..and Orhan Bey will be with us as well.
Wait for me at Kurtbogan tomorrow
truth will be revealed, if Allah permits.
-My son.
-Mother.
-Are you alright?
-I am alright, thank Allah.
Hug your son now, Bala.
Dirt covers my son.
However, you will go through what
I went through, a thousand times.
I told you we will survive, my rose.
You did, my Bey.
My Bey.
-Are you alright?
-I am alright, thanks to you.
You are now engaged.
Now, it is time for your wedding.
After we are done with these issues.
Then, we will make a grand wedding,
if Allah permits.
If Allah permits, my Bey.
Come on then.
This Dervish was not good for us, Ulcay.
If the truth about the judge is
revealed, they will find us for sure.
-What will we do?
-It does not matter if..
..wolf's teeth is sharper than jackal.
Jackal's mind will win him the fight always.
I made my move.
Drop that sword.
Commander of Bursa, Alexios.
..is our friend.
If you want live a long life, listen to Ulcay.
-Did you bring Ahmed's killer?
-Bring him!
Feodor. A prisoner sentenced to death.
It does not matter who kills you, right Feodor?
No.
We gave his family a lot of gold for him.
He will do what I say.
The killer of Shahzade Ahmed.
We will play a little game..
..before you die.
Take him.
-Did you send word to Ibrahim Bey?
-He will have it soon.
If he wants his son's
killer, he will come to Bursa.
I will make the alliance we
talked about there as well.
The alliance that will cost Osman his lands.
Olcaytu Khan is after this issue.
The Emperor..
..wants Osman first, then
Yakup and Ibrahim to go away.
Let us get rid of this issue first.
Those upstairs will have what they want.
You just take..
..Ibrahim Bey in your hands.
Alps. From now on, every night..
..there will be communication between
all the alps guarding the perimeter.
Especially in nights like these..
..we will be extra cautious.
Give it here, Hasan.
In the name of Allah.
When the long range arrows
arrive the alps on the other side..
..they will answer.
If they do not answer..
Then we will know that,
there will be an attack on tribe.
As you command, my Shahzade.
Do not worry, arrows will be shot.
Thank you, come on.
The existence of Holofira disturbs your peace.
What's wrong with you, my
Hatun? Why don't you smile?
Nothing, I'm all right.
-Tell me.
-I feel an emptiness inside me.
I wish it hadn't been like this.
I wish.
But it will get better. It'll all be all right.
I hope so.
Attention! Osman Bey!
-Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you too.
Here, have a seat.
After all those evil things...
...thanks to my Creator...
...we're together again.
Despite all that lie, slander, envy
and dishonor, the winner is love again.
My son Alaeddin, my daughter-in-law Gonca.
You followed the word of your ancestors.
You've been loyal to our customs.
And you've always gone after your love.
I'm happy with you as your father.
-Thank you, my Bey.
If Allah permits, soon we will
-reveal your innocence.
-If Allah permits.
-If Allah permits, my Bey.
-After that,
we will make the most glorious ceremony.
-If Allah permits.
Your family, your parents
will understand this situation
and they will be with us.
If Allah permits, my Bey.
Tough paths cannot be
crossed with soft hearted ones.
Holofira.
You risked your own life
and you did your best for me and for my children.
Thank you. Thank you.
From now on
you are our daughter as well.
Thank you, Osman Bey.
I see you as a father.
May my Creator make us the key
for blessing and lock for the evil.
-Aameen.
May He always give us the
opportunity to live a day like this.
If Allah permits.
Come on now.
In the name of Allah,
the merciful, the compassionate.
Thank you, my Bey.
In the name of Allah, the merciful,
the compassionate
Understand the game well. You
are Cerkutay Bey, don't forget.
No, it's wrong. Cerkutay Bey's heart is here.
And you'll do this.
Look at this.
My Bey. Look,
I've brought you bear grease
you can rub it on your beard.
It will shine it and make it look better.
Father, are you out of your mind?
This is goat hair, not a real beard.
Thnak you, my Bey. Thank you.
I didn't know that.
Ghazi, look at me.
Don't make me regret that I accepted it.
You might say something wrong
-It'd be a shame for Osman Bey.
-Father.
Don't meddle in my business, don't hinder me.
I'll be free, I'll get out
and I'll say anything I want. That's enough!
-Ghazi.
-No.
No, Cerkutay Bey. Now get out of my sight!
-Look what you're saying.
-Alps.
Take this alp out of my tent.
-Yes, my Bey.
-Stop.
-Who's that?
-Baysungur Alp.
-Who's he?
-It's you.
-Is he me?
-Yes.
Take a good care of your appearance.
Your appearance is the most important thing.
And don't embarrass your father.
Come on, Cerkutay Bey. Come on.
Yes, my Bey.
Praise be.
My Gonca. You don't eat anything.
No, I'm eating, Alaeddin.
Germiyanoglu Border - Frontier Market
Oh, the smell of my daughter.
What have you done?
You disobeyed my orders! How
could you do this to me, daughter?
What kind of test did you put me into?
Would I ever put you in a caged tent?
Don't do this, father.
It's not your fault.
Don't be upset.
How can I not be upset? My Gonca
my rose-scented daughter
turned against her father.
She said you're not my father anymore.
It's not Gonca's fault as well.
Alaeddin fooled her. The Kayis
have turned my sister against us.
Osman.
Osman will pay its price.
He took my daughter.
He destroyed my reputation.
I'll make him pay for this.
Attention!
Osman Bey.
What happened, Cerkutay?
-Osman Bey.
-What Osman Bey?
Peace be upon you.
Ghazi...
Peace be upon you too
Infidels, our enemies surrounded us.
Cerkutay!
On the horizons of Sogut and Yenisehir...
...signs have appeared.
It seems that friends and enemies
will unite and come upon us.
My Bey, there are a few of us,
how will we deal with these enemies?
No! Don't!
Don't, Cerkutay! Many times, the few...
...have defeated the many.
Oh Praise be! -Did my heart...
...my effort, disappear that
they demand our lives from us?
Oh praise be!
Alps! Stand up and get ready!
Draw your swords!
I swear by the soul of my
ancestor Oghuz Khan that...
...the days when we will stand at the
gates of Mekece castle and Bursa are near!
-Allah is the Greatest!
-O Praise be!
For the love of Ghazis who say Allah Allah!
Allah is the Greatest!
For the love of martyrs who
were martyred with bloody swords!
Allah is the Greatest!
For the love of mothers who are
waiting for victory and praying for us!
Run to the infidels!
Allah is the Greatest!
Allah is the Greatest! Praise be!
Osman Bey...
Come. -Come closer.
Come here!
Did you hear what he said?
Osman Bey... Come here.
Let me see your beard.
Osman Bey... You made a beard out of goat hair.
Where is your mouth?
-Here, my Bey.
Look at his ring.
Praise be, praise be!
You did not get mad, right, my Osman Bey?
-No.
Why would I? Why would I get mad?
We don't just see you as children.
Our fathers also raised us with the fire of gaza.
Look... Now we have become a magnificent sycamore.
If Allah permits, we will get even stronger.
If Allah permits, my Bey.
Orhan
Alaeddin!
Just like Ghazi and Osman Bey...
...I want grandchildren from you...
...who burn with the fire of gaza. Know that.
-If Allah permits, my Bey.
We will have grandchildren, Osman Bey. We will.
And our glorious sycamore will
get bigger and stronger, if Allah permits.
Our lineage will continue.
Come on now, Osman Bey. Go to
your Alps. They are all waiting for you.
You deserved a meal. Eat now.
Yes my Osman Bey.
Come on Alps.
Beys.
You will come with me.
Gunduz Bey. No sooner than tomorrow...
...you and Alaeddin will be at the place
where Mekece's preparations are made.
-Okay, Osman Bey.
-Yes my Bey.
Orhan. You will be with Mehmed..
...and that jackal Olcay.
You will watch the investigation that...
...Yunus Emre will conduct.
-Yes my Bey.
Everyone will be cautious. But Alaeddin...
You will be even more careful.
We couldn't prove your innocence.
Gonca coming with us will drive Mehmet and...
...Yakup crazy.
They can make a move at any time.
Don't worry, father. We will find
the killer as soon as possible...
...and we will prove our innocence,
if Allah permits.
If we cannot...
...we cannot prevent people
from shedding brothers' blood.
We prevented it today. But, we cannot
know what tomorrow is going to bring.
Slit my throat, Ibrahim Bey.
You set our son's killer free today...
...send me to my son. Slit my throat!
Hatun... Don't...
What should I do, Ibrahim Bey?
Didn't Osman get away with what he did, huh?
How could you do this to us?
-Hatun!
Everyone on these lands believe
and trust the words of Yunus Emre.
The man put his turban in front of us as a shroud!
How could I stand against him?
You should have stood against him as Ibrahim Bey.
Let alone a Dervish, no matter who comes...
...you should've stood against them -Hatun!
You are making me and yourself commit sin.
Yunus Emre stepped in. And I trust him.
Don't worry. He will solve this issue.
Osman Bey will organize a celebration
after our funeral and have a good time...
...and we will wait. Is that true?
Can I come in?
Come in.
Ibrahim Bey, this letter was sent to you.
If you want to find your son's murderer...
...we want to host you in Bursa castle.
Bursa Commander Alexius.
What does that Bursa's Commander Alexius...
..know about our son's killer?
You will go there, right my Bey?
What is the cost of these?
What is the cost of these? -It is a lifetime.
A lifetime.
A lifetime. A lifetime.
I hope it's good!
Bala.
In the name of Allah, the merciful,
the compassionate.
Allah is the greatest.
Peace and mercy of Allah
shall be upon you.
What's going on?
-It's alright. It's alright.
-Cerkutay.
Osman Bey... Where is he?
I don't know, Bala Hatun.
Oghuz. Alps.
-Where is Osman Bey?
Since we stood watch here
...nobody has come out, Bala Hatun.
-You should stand watch properly!
-Calm down, Cerkutay.
If he has a plan in his mind, no
watchmen can see Osman Bey.
You're right, Bala Hatun.
Mother Bala, is my father in the tent?
No, son. It seems Osman Bey is looking for
new destinations to ride his horse towards.
-Has he gone somewhere?
-They say nobody left the tent.
-We don't know.
-I hope there isn't a problem.
No problem. Osman Bey must have a plan.
Everybody get back to work, come on.
I'll go see Yunus Emre for the investigation.
If you hear from my father, let me know, mother.
Alright. Stay safe, son.
Thank you.
Oghuz.
-Prepare the horses.
-As you order, my Bey.
-Come on, Cerkutay.
-Be careful.
The dream you saw is adorned
with secrets, Osman Bey.
Each of them is to be cut open.
But the thing you saw is a covered fact.
You're supposed to remove the cover.
All that fog points out that.
A fact hidden with a cover of evil.
-Well...
The dream I saw... The ring in the fish's mouth...
The smell on my hand... It's still here.
It smells like the sea.
Well... What does the mountain stand for?
Both the fish and the ring point out the conquests.
And what is blowing from Mount Kesis
towards you is the wind of conquests.
Every wind awaits a flag, Osman Bey.
And Mount Kesis misses the flag of Islam.
It expects you to end this longing.
It awaits the reunion.
It awaits you.
Then I need to fulfill the longing now.
Have a safe journey.
Thank you, thank you, Yunus Emre.
Here we go.
O Mount Kesis! The azan of Muhammad
(PBUH) will resound in your sky...
...and many believers will worship at your feet.
Sooner or later.
Come! The best quality here!
Nobody has better
goods than Hristo.
Oh Bursa...
What time are you waiting for?
If we're looking for the truth,
we should want to find it first.
And everybody who wants to find the truth...
...is here.
Let's find it and get rid of the
slander on my brother, Yunus Emre.
The truth cannot be hidden, Orhan Bey.
Slander can only hit the slanderer.
-Don't be worrying.
-Okay.
While looking for the killer, will we start
to look thinking Alaaddin is innocent?
Didn't you start by blaming him...
...while there was no evidence?
Where should we start, Mehmed Bey?
From where it started. From the frontier market.
Didn't the frontier market
get investigated several times?
Place isn't separated from time.
What couldn't be seen then can be seen now.
We'll start there.
Whatever you command, Yunus Emre.
But this time, Alaaddin Bey
and Gonca Hatun will be there.
Because the matter might be twisted easily.
They are banned to enter the frontier market.
Sultan of the Words has spoken.
We should speak no more, Mehmed Bey.
Not at all, not at all.
Everybody has words and should speak.
So the truth can be revealed.
For this reason, Alaaddin Bey
and Gonca Hatun will speak too.
It's appropriate for them to be in
the market about the investigation.
Alright.
Let's go then.
May Allah keep your journey safe.
-Thank you.
-Thank you, Yunus Emre.
God bless you.
Thanks. I'm grateful to you, stranger.
What are you looking for here?
Do you know everyone here?
You quickly realized I was a stranger.
The people of this city can't know themselves...
..as well as I know them.
But what are you looking for here?
What a stranger would look for.
-Job.
That's easy. Yet...
-What can you do?
-Anything.
I'm a quick learner. Well...
Great Bursa... Rich Bursa...
I'm sure it won't leave me hungry.
It will certainly fill your stomach.
It has fertile lands.
God still smiles at us despite our sins.
Silk... The greatest blessing in Bursa.
You say silk, huh?
The silk..
..goes to many lands from here.
Yes, however, it will not be like this forever.
Why did you say that?
Everything seems to be in order here.
Yes, the city looks good.
Because all the dirt goes under.
The only thing that is not
present in Bursa is justice.
And everyone allows it.
Is that why you are not with the
church? You are begging around?
If there was no justice..
-..there would be nothing.
You said that right, stranger.
What about Osman Bey?
What did you hear about him?
-They say his eyes are on this place.
-Osman.
I've heard his name before.
Even if we do not believe in the
same religion, they say he is just.
What about work? Where is it?
Look, stranger. You see..
..everyone is after their own food here.
The merchant you passed by was hiring.
He is our biggest supporter. Go to him.
-He will give you a job.
-Thank you.
Strength to your elbows, Bacis!
-Thank you Bala Hatun.
-Welcome.
Time goes fast, right?
We were just a tribe of hundred tents yesterday.
However, now we have our
banner at many cities, thank Allah.
-Thank Allah. -However..
..we did not just grow with
our lands and our trade.
We grew with our houses
as well, just like our tribe.
Now, it is time to..
..do some work, brides.
My daughter Elcim..
..I've heard your skills
at your tribe. That is why..
..you will be in charge of carpet house.
I will do what is needed, Bala Hatun.
Thank you.
Holofira, my daughter.
If you accept, I have work for you as well.
You will be in charge of non-muslim merchants..
..who do business in our lands.
Osman Bey wants it as well.
If I can make a difference, of course.
Of course I will do it, Bala Hatun.
Thank you.
My daughter Gonca, you will..
..be in charge of Turkmen tribes'
business, just like you were before.
As you say, Bala Hatun.
Fatma Hatun!
Mother.
About your duty.
From now on, Fatma Hatun..
..you are in charge of the training
of new hatuns came to Baciyans.
Mother.
-My dear daughter.
-As you say, mother.
-Alright, may you do your duties well.
-Ameen.
-Strength to your elbows.
-Thank you.
It seems you gave up on leaving.
Yes, for now.
I will do the task Osman Bey gave me, Elcim Hatun.
So you do not keep your promise.
Elcim.
Osman Bey and Bala Hatun gave her the duty.
Are you questioning their decision?
Gonca, Holofira was the one
telling she was going to leave.
I just say what I heard from her.
I changed my mind.
I will be here for a while.
I will not leave, Elcim.
-My Gonca.
-Alaeddin.
-My Gonca. -Alaeddin.
My brother sent word. We are
going to Frontier Marketplace.
I will come with you. I will not leave you alone.
You owe us your earnings.
-However, you are hiding the gold.
-I do not have any strength left.
I am giving you all I have.
Who are you?
Who are you I said!
I owe you. I was about to give them all I had.
I was finished. They would've
taken it all if it wasn't for you.
Maybe my life as well.
-Take the half, please.
-I did not save your life for gold.
I just did what is right. Who are they?
Criminals who feed on merchants.
No one says a word for their interest.
How can I repay you?
-I want a job.
-I am looking for a man as well.
There is no trust left in Bursa.
-What do you do?
-I do everything but this.
I have a few carts of goods to be carried.
If you put them down I will pay you for it.
-Where do you need them put?
-That is easy, you are not from here.
-Where do you stay?
-I do not stay at anywhere.
Since you are my apprentice now..
..I will take care of the place
you stay and the food you need.
Let us go to the inn this evening.
We can eat, what do you say?
Just tell me where do you
need your goods to be put.
-Tell me, so that we can deserve meal.
-You haven't told me your name.
My name.
-..is Nicola.
And I am Hristo.
Come on, to work.
You've heard the guards.
No one has seen or heard anything.
While you were keeping us hostage in your tribe,
Osman Bey came and questioned my alps.
My alps don't know anything.
Are we going to talk about the past here
or are we going to search for truth, Yakup Bey?
Osman Bey heard that Ulcay was there
in the Frontier Marketplace that night.
Maybe Ulcay saw something?
Ulcay.
I'm a
man of Ibrahim Bey.
But Ahmed, Shahzade Ahmed
was my friend.
If I saw who killed him, would I let him live?
Ahmed was my brother.
People of Frontier Marketplace
Didn't anyone see this?
If anyone saw it
or anyone is hiding it, show yourself.
We'll protect his life and property.
We just want him to speak up and reveal the truth.
I support what Bala Hatun said. If
anyone know anything, speak up.
I saw it.
Come here.
I'm Marcus, one of the Christian
merchants of Frontier Marketplace.
Beys were so angry at each other that
I couldn't say it because I was afraid.
So? Why are you talking now?
A dervish named Yunus Emre calmed the Beys down.
That's what encouraged me.
Tell us what you saw then.
When Alaeddin Bey and others left the tent
someone entered the tent.
Who entered?
Ulcay.
Ulcay?
Yes, but before him, someone else entered the tent.
-Who is he?
-He left with a bloody dagger.
He entered before Ulcay.
Who's that man? Who? Tell me!
Tell me so I'll spare your life!
Theodor. Merchant Theodor!
Where is he? Where is he? Where is he?
-Where is he?
-Calm down. Stop!
Let them man speak.
He has a house in Dargic. He must be there.
Why would Theodor do such a thing?
What problem did he have with Ahmed Bey?
We'll find it out from him Mehmed Bey. Come on.
Let's go to the place he said.
Melike Hatun.
You've seen it, right?
The killer is not my child.
I won't be at ease until I find the
killer and kill him with my own hands.
-Let the truth be revealed.
-I hope you will be at ease when you see it.
Otherwise we will have further issues.
Yakup Bey.
Can we talk?
Here, get some rest.
Where are they coming from?
-These
come from the villages of Bursa. This is raw silk.
We process it and make fabric.
The value of the silk
determines the value of the fabric.
When fine workmanship and craftsmanship
are involved, the value of silk increases
-ten or even twenty times.
-Silk, is that so?
So you're saying silk.
-That's great.
-It is.
We provide the clothes of all the kings
lords and dukes of Europe.
The source of richness of Bursa is silk.
So,
Which villages does this raw silk come from?
St. Peter's is the best place for this.
They also make good ones in Karlitas.
The profit from this is good, but
then they come to us and extort money.
You mentioned that some stay silent
-for their own benefits. Who are they?
-Soldiers,
commanders, and also the Lord himself.
Excuse me.
Yes, ma'am. Welcome.
Hristo's stall has the most beautiful fabrics.
Its color is beautiful, can you open it for me?
Oh Bursa, I've become a worker for you.
Tell me what you have to say and then get out.
You've heard about what happened, Yakup Bey.
We have nothing to do with Ahmed Bey's death.
It's not my concern.
If you don't have anything else to say, then leave.
Come on Alaeddin, let's leave.
Don't, Yakup Bey. Don't.
Put your anger and grudge aside...
...and listen to us with your heart.
You... you are Gonca's father.
Have you just remembered that I was her father?
You abducted my daughter from my tribe.
What about you?
You disobeyed your father's words.
I never promised anyone anything, father.
You never disobeyed me.
I promised them because I trusted you.
I trusted my daughter's
loyalty to me and to her family.
But... it was actually rotten.
Yakup Bey.
Despite everything that happened...
...I came here as Alaeddin, the
husband of your daughter, Gonca.
I wanted to end her pain.
So she could make peace with her father and family.
I said my last word to your Hatun, Alaeddin.
I don't have a daughter.
My daughter died.
Don't cry, my rose. Don't cry, my Gonca.
I expected grace from you.
But apparently... your heart is as hard as a stone.
So be it.
Let your mother and father turn their backs.
I will be your family, my rose. Don't worry.
Come on, my Gonca. Come on.
Guests of Commander Alexius have come.
They must've prepared a great feast.
The guests of Commander Alexius...
Who are they?
-They said the Lord of Mekece would come.
And a Turk Bey.
Turk Bey? -Yes.
Who is that Turk Bey, huh? Let's go...
..and see their feast.
Go, sure. We are done anyway.
Don't come to the inn late at night.
You forgot your gold!
-There is no need.
I'm not going far, you can
give it to me in the evening.
A mother in pain..
Which black magic...
..can ease your heart?
Do you know who I am?
I can see...
You are lost.
You are burning with the fire of revenge.
Your son's fiancee...
Her Bey... You want to destroy them.
The one who killed my son must be killed.
I want black magic!
I can do the magic.
But you're after the wrong person.
That Bey's son did not kill your son.
Who was it then? Who? Who killed my son?
Listen to the bell...
...to find the murderer Melike Hatun.
You will find him.
Come on. Go and find him.
Good job, old lady.
Olcay said he would work with you in the future.
Alps... We will split into
three and surround the house.
Come on, in the name of Allah!
The Righteous!
Now! I will ask you for once.
If you don't answer my question...
..I will cut your heads off.
Theodor... Where is merchant Theodor?
He is not here.
-Where is he if he is not here?
There, my Orhan Bey! -Theodor...
Hasan! Take them!
You traitor..
You have nowhere left to run, Theodor.
We know you killed Shahzade Ahmed.
Now..
Now I will take you back for the court.
Orhan...
I won't let the man who...
...killed my Shahzade breathe again.
Today, I am the justice.
Stay back.
-Or I won't hesitate killing you.
-Orhan.
I will kill this man today.
No.
I can take your life right here.
We are trying to close this issue
and you are trying to shed blood.
Don't.
We will take this dog to the people.
We will not decide what to
do with him, our Beys will.
Alps!
Your life has no importance..
..to me, Ulcay.
I can feed you to wolves, know that.
Come on.
Orhan Bey is dangerous,
Ulcay. He does not hesitate.
He has sharp tooth like his father.
However, I can tear both of their teeth apart.
Nightmare of Turks, protector of Byzantine..
..Lord of Mekkece, Matteos!
Grand Bey of Turks, Candaroglu Ibrahim Bey!
-Welcome, Beys.
-Where is he?
Where is that murderer?
This show is for you, Ibrahim Bey.
First, let us enjoy it.
I will take your plans down.
Ibrahim Bey.
Did he kill my Ahmed, Ulcay?
Yes, Melike Hatun.
If it was up to me, I would
have killed him on the road.
However, they interrupted.
Pick him up.
-Did you kill him?
-Yes, I killed him!
-Why did you kill him?
-Why did you kill him, he was my only son?
He was my reason to breathe.
You killed me by killing him as well.
How did you do it?
When I entered the caged tent..
..he came to his senses after
seeing me. I punched him twice first.
I told him that this here is the land of Rome.
I took my chance of killing a Turk!
You are just bugs who invaded these lands!
-Is that why you killed Ahmed?
-Why did you think?
Did that not satisfy you?
We will kill you all. Those shiny tribes of yours..
..your palaces, we will destroy them all!
Look at this dog..
..who earns in our marketplace!
Shut it, dog! Mehmed..
..from now on, do not let anyone
enter the marketplace you don't know.
-What did you do after?
-I picked him up and went for his throat.
I told him that breathing in
the holy land is forbidden.
He resisted, wanted to live.
I choked him and stabbed him in the chest.
Who are you serving to?
It does not matter anymore.
That is how it will be.
Those who oppress Turks will find hell.
My Ahmed. Sleep well now.
My son.
-Thank Allah.
-Thank Allah, mother.
-Hristo!
-Come on, Nicola.
They make the best stew here.
Come on in.
I don't know what they are
doing with a Bey of Turks.
They must have a reason. Or
they wouldn't be welcomed in Bursa.
Commander Alexios is a wise man.
Must've had some tricks up his sleeve.
-Didn't you like it, Nikola?
-Well—
On the contrary, I loved it.
Innkeeper! Bring whatever you have.
Give more.
We're Commander Aleksios' guests.
Turkish dog is here again.
Commander Aleksios will ruin them soon.
It won't take long.
You're pushing my patience, commander.
Don't dwell on this matter any longer.
Where is my son's killer?
Your man Ulcay... Mehmed Orhan and he already...
...caught the killer.
In fact, Melike Hatun killed the murderer herself.
What are you talking about?
Are you trying to fool me?
I already gave you the killer, Ibrahim Bey.
How did you? How?
How did you know what we didn't know?
You set your eyes on Orhan's family.
But don't forget about...
...Rome watching you all the time.
What? Are you not getting us watched?
My son's killer...
My Ahmed's killer...
..is dead, huh?
He's dead, huh?
Thank Allah.
Well..
Who?
-Who planned this? -You should find it out.
gave you what you wanted.
Now it's our turn to take.
Let's talk about our alliance
we've been discussing.
Go ahead.
You'll give us your herds with a cheaper price.
Bursa and Nikea will be
blessed with meat this year.
We won't only have herds but also horses.
And we'll equipped with your swords...
...forged with fine steel.
I already told Lord.
Neither Yakup Bey nor I...
...want you to be equipped with our swords.
It's against our morals.
Alright then.
Osman having the wind at his
back will keep marching freely.
And very soon he will unite...
...all Turks under one flag.
Will those swords and horses...
...protect you then?
There's hostility between you
and him. If you don't work with us,
...Osman will be a bigger trouble for you.
When you seal the agreement, the
silk will be sold in your markets too.
We'll grow richer together with this trade network.
Then nobody will be able to harm...
...either your or me, Ibrahim Bey.
Wrong.
They can harm you.
Well...
Why are we having this alliance?
To stop Osman.
Good. But...
If we can't stop him,
...Osman will hit the heathens for sure.
What is in your mind?
You need to give Mekece under my command.
If I keep the castle, Osman can't attack.
If he does
...no Beys will stand behind me.
This is the only agreement
which is beneficial for us.
Otherwise, forget about the alliance.
That's unacceptable.
Who says, Lord?
Everybody should sacrifice for Rome.
Ibrahim Bey is right.
This is a good way to first stop Osman...
...and then to destroy him.
May our alliance be everlasting.
May it be a blessing.
Yes, Ibrahim Bey.
-You still haven't given my gold.
-Oh, my silly mind.
-You said there was no rush.
-There wasn't, but now there is.
Innkeeper.
I treat two men next to me
to dessert and sherbet.
This table.
May God bless you, we're grateful.
You're grateful to me?
What about Commander Alexios
-who protects all this richness?
-I don't get it?
Those men.
They sit in our holy table.
Find out what's their intention.
He's right.
You've been working all day and sweating.
Are you going to spend that gold for this?
Maybe it's because I'll be repaid in kind.
Hey, you.
Did your Bey leave you hungry
that you're at the gates of Bursa?
Do not bother us.
The richness of our property
is almost equal to Bursa.
If you were not hungry, you
would not have come to Bursa.
Are you after our silk?
Soon your famous silk will
be sold in our marketplace.
Then we will get a share of your wealth.
Now, the commander of
Bursa and our Bey are friends.
What will you give in exchange?
We will sell you
Turks' glorious swords and horses.
We will share our power with you.
-This will strengthen our friendship.
-What are you saying?
Do you think we need your friendship
your swords or your horses?
I got what I wanted.
Thankfully, we got rid of the
slander against my brother.
Thankfully, brother. Thankfully.
If my father was here so we would be at ease.
-Mother, what are you thinking about?
-This time I don't know either.
But your father must have something in his mind.
We will all find out when he returns.
Come on, enjoy your food.
Come on.
In the name of Allah, the merciful,
the compassionate.
Mother. You know what?
Since my brothers got married
I've never had headache.
You don't have a headache either, do you?
A little bit.
-Tell me.
-They're so rich, my Bey.
They spend the money properly.
They strengthen the eastern walls.
Our catapults can only dust the walls.
Their soldiers are well-trained. They're
not like the ones in the castle or citadel.
You don't say a single good word, Tugay.
What do you think? How are people?
My Bey, they cornered us in
the inn, we almost died there.
People don't like us. They
will unite if there's a siege.
So you say that it is impossible to take Bursa?
Bursa. It is a dream for you.
-I'll turn it into reality.
-But,
We took my child's killer.
Thankfully.
Go after him!
Commander is a smart man
He sent him after us to find out our move.
-Aykurt! How's the situation, Aykurt?
-My Shahzade.
We've been working ceaselessly day and night.
I hope it will be ready on time.
Praise be to my brave boys.
Praise be. They're working like bees, my Shahzade.
-What's this, Aykurt?
-My Shahzade.
Didn't I tell you that these jugs won't be big?
Who told you to make them like this?
I told them, Alaeddin Bey.
The bigger the flying flame
the harder the impact.
Don't do this, Gunduz Bey. You'll
embarrass us against the enemy.
I calculate their distances with algebra.
If the flying flame is so big, the
catapults cannot throw them far.
They will fall before even they get to the walls.
-I thought that...
-Don't, Gunduz Bey.
These require fine calculations.
Please leave it to me.
All right, I got it, Alaeddin Bey.
My age and experience is enough.
You don't need to repeat anymore.
Everyone is doing their best, Alaeddin Bey.
There's no need to get angry.
Elcim Hatun.. -Alaeddin.
We're all here for this, brother.
We will correct the mistakes.
Everyone has the same intention.
Come on. Go and check the catapults.
Alright, okay.
There was no intentional mistake, Orhan.
He who knows the elder is greater than the elder.
Your brother Alaeddin learned algebra,
it seems he didn't learn this one.
Ah.
Where are you going to run this
time? You have nowhere to go.
-Why are you following me?
-I don't know you, sir.
-I'm just a beggar.
-Where did you get these clothes?
A man gave me this gold coin and the clothes.
-He wanted me to run. -What did he look like?
My eyes can't see well. He
gave me gold and clothes.
He looks like an angel now.
Move. Come on.
-What will we tell our Bey?
-What happened. Let's go.
He humiliated me before all the alps.
Now alps...
..will doubt my decisions.
Alaaddin can't harm your authority, father.
How many battles did he even
fight? He'll pay for his impertinence.
Arrogance, daughter... Arrogance preys on minds.
He got acquitted. He gained Germiyan's support.
And now he's got arrogant.
But I know what to do to him.
How is Gunduz Bey doing, Elcim Hatun?
What happened upset my father, Orhan Bey.
But what really upset him was your attitude.
-Elcim...
Alaaddin..
...insulted my father before you.
Why did you let him? Why
didn't you defend my father?
Can the obvious be denied, Elcim Hatun?
Besides, my brother Alaaddin
is right about the catapults.
Even if he is right,
...he can't insult my father before everyone.
-Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you too, my Bey.
-Peace be upon you too.
Welcome, my Bey.
We're looking forward to hearing your news, but...
First, I have good news for you.
...first I have good news to give you.
Tell me Bala. Go ahead, Bala.
Shahzade Ahmed's killer was found, my Bey!
Alaeddin and Gonca are now free.
I know... I know for sure.
But..
The truth in the matter
where the infidel is involved...
...always makes me doubt.
But now, that's not our concern. Our concern is...
...greater and more difficult.
We are listening to you, Osman Bey.
Fitna and evilness are rising in Bursa.
Ibrahim Bey, the commander of Bursa and...
...the Lord of Mekece have become allies.
This darkness tries to cover the light.
It is a matter aimed at destroying us.
Our preparations are not complete. But...
We are ready to fight and die, Osman Bey.
We have no time left! We will act immediately!
The Alps will besiege Mekece.
We will go after them before this alliance...
...comes at us.
-If Allah permits.
-If Allah permits my Bey.
A war council will be planned.
We'll take immediate action. As soon as possible.
Germiyanoglu Border - Frontier Market
The merchants and people who withdrew from...
...the Karacahisar market
have now come to our market.
When news of the trade agreement we
made with Bursa and Mekece spreads...
...the market will become even richer.
With this agreement, I have
both found my son's murderer...
...and put an end to Osman's trade.
Soon, not even a pouch of
gold will remain in his treasury.
In the end, Osman will be destroyed.
Bursa and Iznik will be ours.
But first, we will defend Mekece.
Mehmed and Olcay...
...will secure Mekece.
My Bey...
Osman Bey is marching with his
Alps towards the Mekece castle.
Prepare the horses! We are setting out!
-Yes my Bey!
The day we have been waiting for has come!
Osman will be disgraced!
He will either behave or the
dark soil will be watered with blood!
My Bey! Where are you going?
To make Iznik kneel and to
make crusaders bow down, Hatun!
Come on.
Near Mekece Castle
Lord!
If you surrender...
...I will let you and your soldiers...
...to go to the closest castle.
What if I do not surrender?
-Then..
...I will destroy the walls that you trust.
I will kill the soldiers that you trust...
Now make your decision.
My mercy, or my furor?
Give me some time to think, Osman Bey.
I am giving you time until the sunset. Or else...
...the fire of cannonballs will
brighten the night, know that.
I don't think he will surrender, my Bey.
-He is trying to gain time, Osman Bey.
-So he's waiting for help from someone
-We will see.
We will see.
My soldiers!
The enemy has come to our walls. We
are going to protect the honor of Mekece!
Fight for your honor!
Either Osman dies today...
...or we will meet Jesus!
Death to Osman! Death to Osman!
The Lord hasn't said
anything, Osman Bey.
Then we will only hear
the sound of cannonballs.
They will think that we are going to attack.
Wait for my move. Open the doors!
Come on, my lions!
Walk!
Now I will teach you how you can win a war...
...without using your sword.
Alps! Prepare the flying flames!
Make catapults movable!
It's almost sunset! Come on!
-Praise be! My brother...
-Brother?
Alaeddin... Gunduz Bey is upset with
you. Why did you say those things to him?
-Why are you asking me why, brother?
-I am just asking you Alaeddin.
I just reminded him his
duty. I reported his weakness.
Everyone must fulfill their duties if
they do not want to hear those things.
Even if it is Gunduz Bey,
even if it is your father in law...
...I cannot ignore such mistake, brother.
-Alaeddin...
Of course, you are not going to
ignore it. But you know, my brother...
We have a way for everything.
You've embarrassed Gunduz
Bey in front of all the Alps.
Brother...
Calm down, Alaeddin. Calm down.
My Bey... The doors of the castle are open.
They are coming this way. They will surrender.
No... Don't be so sure.
Lords are on the way. They will
act as if they are going to surrender.
But... they are going there to fight.
-My Shahzade...
Let's see what Osman Bey is going to do now.
We will see, Gokmen. We will see.
It is time for war now. Come on!
Yes my Shahzade. Come on!
Come on!
Get ready!
Osman Bey! We did not come here to surrender...
-We're here to fight!
-What is he counting on?
I hope it's not what I think it is.
Come on, boys!
Put Ibrahim Bey's banners
and hang them over the walls.
Here, the victory of the jackals!
My Bey, someone's coming. Ibrahim Bey and
Yakup Bey. They're coming with their armies.
Do whatever you want.
Try anything you want, the
blood won't stop in the vein.
It is not enough that you two are united,
but you are also allied with the infidels?
It's not alliance, Osman Bey.
We don't form alliance with infidels.
-So?
Mekece Castle
Mekece lands
and Mekece's trade
are under my protection.
And Lord Mateus is now subject to me.
We have come to turn you from the wrong path.
Taking a castle that belongs to Muslims
is not something a Bey like you would do.
Osman Bey. Tell your alps,
let them return to their tribes.
So don't let them say that
The glorious Osman Bey was trying
to take the castle of a Muslim Bey
he caused the death of his alps
and, as if that were not enough
he lost his own life.
You stand between us and the infidels.
Taking a castle from a Muslim is unbecoming of us.
But keep it in mind that...
...taking a castle from a hypocrite
is Osman Bey's responsibility!
Visit turkision.com for more!